sway.com 2007-02-05

# Sway Drive

What is SwayDrive and why is my information needed? 

SwayDrive is a Web based service providing online storage space and related services that customers can use to store, share, access, and protect important files. This policy explains the personal information we collect on the SwayDrive site, and how we use it. If you are an GBS member, the GBS Member Privacy Policy will continue to apply to the collection and use of your personal information, except as described below. 

What personal information does SwayDrive collect from me? 

SwayDrive collects personal information when you register, including your first name, last name, password, and valid user ID or screen name. When you upgrade to or register for a paid account, SwayDrive will ask for your credit card information in order to provide you uninterrupted service. Once registered, you are part of the SwayDrive community, a customer account is created, and you can take full advantage of SwayDrive's services. 

After you register, we may ask you for additional personal information from time to time, such as when you respond to a survey or request for information about your preferences, enter a contest or promotion sponsored by SwayDrive, and when you report a problem with the service or with your account. If you contact SwayDrive we keep a record of that interaction, including any email you send. A link is included to this Privacy Policy wherever SwayDrive collects personal information. 

What are cookies and how does SwayDrive use them? 

In order to provide a personalized service, SwayDrive uses cookies to store some information about your account. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server that is stored on your computer's hard drive. SwayDrive uses both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. Generally, we use cookies: 

To establish an authenticated session with the service when you login to your SwayDrive account using our web interface. When you use SwayDrive's web interface to access your account, logging in will require that you accept a session ID cookie. When you close your web browser, the session ID cookie will terminate. 

To remember some of your basic account preferences in order to deliver a better, more personalized service. A persistent cookie may be set when you register, "Sign In," or use the SwayDrive web interface to record certain application settings and other preferences. 

You have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies, you will be unable to access SwayDrive account via the web interface. 

SwayDrive may also record your IP address for system administration, monitoring, and fraud prevention purposes. 

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by SwayDrive only and does not cover the use of cookies or web beacons by any advertisers on the site or any other business partners. Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. 

How does SwayDrive use my information? 

SwayDrive uses your personal information to operate and improve the service, as well as to communicate with you and respond to your inquiries. 

SwayDrive will use your e-mail address to send you e-mails that are generated when you perform certain functions within the service. The types of e-mails that are sent include, but are not limited to, welcome e-mails, share e-mails, and cancellation e-mails. 

SwayDrive does research on customer demographics and behavior based on the information you provide and how you use the service. We gather information about how you use the service using log files, tracking pixels, and database history tables. We do this to better understand and serve our customers. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated and de-identified basis. 

With whom does SwayDrive share my information? 

SwayDrive will not disclose any of your SwayDrive personal information except when we have your permission; in response to legal process or under the circumstances described below. SwayDrive does not sell or give access to our customer e-mail list or other customer profile information to third parties. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed. 

Data in the Aggregate: SwayDrive may disclose aggregated statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. 

Special Circumstances: SwayDrive may also grant access to or disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating SwayDrive's Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) SwayDrive's rights or property, other SwayDrive users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. SwayDrive may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it. 

Service Providers: When you sign up for an SwayDrive premium paid service, we will pass relevant information to a third party credit card processing company. The credit card account number is encrypted for added security during these transmissions. We prohibit these companies from retaining, sharing, storing or using this personally identifiable information for any other purpose. 

SwayDrive is a wholly owned subsidiary of GBS LLC, which also performs certain operational functions on behalf of SwayDrive. For example, GBS LLC processes several types of e-mail for SwayDrive, including but not limited to welcome, cancellation and share e-mails. To facilitate these operations, SwayDrive provides GBS LLC with your e-mail address information. 

For GBS Members using SwayDrive, certain GBS offerings may require interactivity with SwayDrive services, and your SwayDrive personal information may be shared with GBS in connection with such offerings. 

Third Party Retail Distributors: If you register for SwayDrive through one of our third party retail distributors, SwayDrive may disclose your email address to that specific third party retail distributor. 

What is SwayDrive's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personal information? 

You can edit your SwayDrive account information at any time by accessing your account using our web interface. Your profile information can be modified by accessing the "My Profile" page once you are logged in. Information associated with your screen name, if applicable, must be modified within the Screen Name Service (SNS).

What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information? 

When you register for an SwayDrive account, the signup page may ask you for sensitive information (such as your credit card number. We use industry-standard SSL encryption to help protect the registration information you provide. 

Your SwayDrive account information and SwayDrive customer profile are password-protected to help ensure that you, and only you, have access to this personal information. You may edit your SwayDrive account information by logging into our web interface using your SwayDrive username and password. 

We require that you do not divulge your password to anyone. SwayDrive will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or e-mail. Also remember to sign out of your SwayDrive account and close your browser window when you finish your work to help ensure that others cannot access your personal information or files if you share a computer with someone or use a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. 

As a global company, SwayDrive has international sites and users all over the world. When you give SwayDrive personal information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information, such as to the United States or other countries. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of the country where you entered it. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, SwayDrive cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or while using the service, and you do so at your own risk. We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical safeguards designed to help protect personal information stored in our systems. 

How SwayDrive uses contact information that you might provide when "Sending a File" or "Sharing a Folder" 

When you use SwayDrive to "Send a File" or "Share a Folder" with someone, you normally enter the intended recipientÂ's e-mail address into the system so that a message can be sent informing him or her of the share. . We do not sell or make those E-mail addresses available to any 3rd parties. 

When you use SwayDrive's "Send a File" feature, you can elect to have the system send a notification message on your behalf by entering the e-mail address(es) of the person(s) with whom you want to share the file. If you prefer, you can instead generate a web link to the file, which can be sent as part of your own message. Send a File notification messages sent by SwayDrive are one-time only messages with the sole intent of notifying the recipient of the shared file. 

Using SwayDrive's "Share a Folder" feature requires that the person with whom you are sharing to have an SwayDrive account to access the folder. If the person with whom you are sharing does not already have an SwayDrive account, a free sharing account will be created for that person when you share the folder. SwayDrive will automatically send an e-mail inviting the person to activate their free account so they can access the folder you have shared. To activate, the sharing account holder will need to register for the service and will need to provide standard information to do so. 

What else should I know about my privacy? 

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. SwayDrive does not control and is not responsible for how others use that information. 

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that SwayDrive is not responsible for the privacy or other practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site. 

Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible online. 

Additional Information 

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to GBS SwayDrivesupport@genralbackup.com. 

Other Resources 

Electronic Frontier Foundation - a civil liberties organization working to protect your rights online. 

Electronic Privacy Information Center - established to focus public attention on emerging civil liberties issues relating to the National Information Infrastructure. 

Privacy Issues Page - from the Center for Democracy and Technology (CDT). 

The EPIC Cookies Page - definitions, links, and news. 

How to Protect Your Privacy - information from the Federal Trade Commission
